JESUS SANTANA

Email:

jaysantanatech@gmail.com

Phone: 470-331-2611

Address: 8000 Waters Ave Apartment #44 Savannah

GA 31406

Website:

www.santanaportfolio.com

PROFILE

I have finished my two-year basic core classes in Georgia Gwinnett College and wish to peruse a job in the tech industry. I took classes for Python, Html, and Css at GGC but later decided to experiment other career choices before committing. I went from being a Banker/Accountant in Associated Credit Union to a Piano/Spanish teacher at The University of West Georgia. Despite my hiatus, I've built computers and explored coding within many linux distros as hobby. My goal is to establish a growing career as a software developer, expanding my knowledge in technology and enhancing my problem solving skills. Frameworks, Languages, and Software are always expanding with new updates and features so my learning journey is never ending.

EXPERIENCE

Call Agent, MCI, Savannah, GA — 2021-Current

I currently work at home as a call representative for MCI. Upon applying, I made a request to my supervisor that after 6 months of working I would could start applying to programming jobs. The opportunity to stay at home to relearn how to code has given me the benefit to enjoy and develop a deeper understanding of programming. Upon working at MCI, I will stay employed until I reach my final goal of landing a career as a software developer.

Veterinary Technician, VCA, Savannah, GA — 2020-2021

Due to the Covid 19 pandemic The University of West Georgia was shut down and I had no way of receiving income for housing. I sought to work starting out in Carrol County Animal Hospital a kennel tech. Upon working there, I was given the privilege by my manager to move up the veterinary industry by moving to Savannah. By relocating, I was immediately promoted to a veterinary tech. My daily tasks consisted of helping set appointments for clients/doctors and giving medications/injections to patients. I set up surgical equipment in surgical packs and helped with surgery in my free time or as needed.

Branch Service Representative, Associated Credit Union, Lawrenceville, GA — 2017-2019

My objectives were to process members' transactions throughout the day and manage phone calls. The primary goal was to educate members on services such as Interest rates, loans and credit cards to identify the best route for their financial needs. I was being trained to become a financial

advisor, however I did not want to pursue it as a career. Early 2019 I decided to become a full time student in college for Piano Pedagogy at University of West Georgia.

Sales Associate/ Frate Team Member, Home Depot, Lawrenceville, GA — 2015-2017

My responsibilities were to inform customers on products and help them choose the right equipment. I also became licensed on driving machinery to help restock and organize space on shelves.

EDUCATION

University Of West Georgia, Carrolton, GA Spanish & Piano Pedagogy 2019

Diving into my passion in teaching, I have extended to become an educational instructor for both Spanish and Fine Arts (Piano Pedagogy). My GPA continued to stay above 3.0 and was awarded scholarships for my performance in playing the Piano. I taught kids to play piano and guitar after school in the Pippin Music Academy for income and experience. I enrolled in the UWG Spanish club as well to teach English and Spanish to local Hispanic/American churches. Unfortunately, Covid-19 hit the schools and colleges in carrolton and my studies were postponed. Upon deeper reflection of my career choice, I decided to revert back into becoming a programmer for a number of reasons. The primary reason being my love for technology.

Georgia Gwinnett College, Lawrenceville, GA Info Technology/Programming 2019

GGC was the first college I attended. My goal was to simply graduate with an Associates Degree. I have always maintained a GPA score above 3.0 and completed all basic courses. Due to my love for technology, I decided to try and spend an additional year to discover how to program. I started taking programming courses and website development classes and deemed it very fascinating. The concept of problem solving and learning a new language was a massive challenge to me. With patience, perseverance, and practice It became straightforward along the way. Seeing as this was my first career choice at the age of 18, I was curious about other professions and decided to explore my options before committing to any career field.

Skills

- · Translating Spanish
- Efficient in Technology (Microsoft Word/Excel)
- Typing speed 50 WPM
- 5 year + Customer Service
- Strong work ethic

- Html/Cs
- Javascript
- Python
- Node.js
- Firebase
- Github
- Glt
- AdobeXD
- MacOS Echosystem

References

Adrian Nunn: Phone: 770-778-4887 Carroll County Animal Hospital Manager

Ashley Thomas: Phone: 770-940-2740 Carroll County Animal Hospital

Surgery Technician

<u>Dr. Steven Lang:</u> Phone: 770-757-7775 Carroll County Animal Hospital Doctor

Kathy Saldana: Phone: 678-938-7150 Associated Credit Union Supervisor

Rosa Yanez: Phone: 770-780-5158 Associated Credit Union Coworker